Matteus **Gaarder**

38a WOODHOUSE ROAD, N12 ORJ, LONDON, ENGLAND CELL 07498 658030 | MAIL matteus.gaarder@gmail.com



PROFILE

Grandmaster Nerd, Tinkerer of Technology, Quadrilingual-international-wanderer, and Creator of Things. My passion for film allowed me to teach a course at Stanford University and provided me the skills to confidently shoot, edit, and produce my own short films, and animations. Captivation for technology lead me to explore and master a wide array of software from Creative Cloud to Excel. As a lover of language I am a speaker of four (including a high-degree of fluency in Japanese, and outstanding English copy-writing, proof-reading, and research abilities).

Education

- Student Coaching
- Lesson Preparation
- Communication
- Curriculum Planning

QUALIFICATION SUMMARY

Video Production

- Camera Operation
- Video Editing
- Visual Effects
- Lighting & Audio

Administration

- Scheduling
- Organisation
- Problem-solving
- Office Processes

WORK EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

Testronic, Suffolk House, Croydon, London, United Kingodm **Localisation Tester**

2021 - Present

I provide quality assurance for games in their final stages of production for leading AAA game developers. I am part of a team that ensures the final product is free from bugs, user experience issues, and language errors before the game's final release to the public.

- Communicate efficiently between large international teams to assure speedy elimination of bugs and UX issues.
- Verify there are no language discrepancies in the game by cross referencing Japanese and English script files.
- Utilise excel knowledge, pivot tables, and online trackers (JIRA), to effectively deal with large datasets in an intuitive way.

TK Trading, The Chase Centre, London, United Kingdom

2020

Warehouse Assistant Manager

Handled phones, tracked incoming orders, and organised outgoing stock to a wide range of businesses across London. recorded inventory and input daily purchases on the internal system using Sage 50, whilst maintaing a high level of quality assurance and customer satisfaction.

Wahlburgers, Covent Garden, London, United Kingdom | Splendid, United Kingdom (various) 2018 – 2020 Line Chef / Caterer

Prepared meals, spearheaded team, maintained high standards, and assured quality. Communicated with colleagues, co-ordinated tasks and shifts, and arranged logistics. Catered for 100+ events, including weddings and festivals, at high profile venues.

- Achieved completion of 200+ tickets per day with team of eight.
- Reduced preparation time for each ticket to under four minutes.

WORK EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS CONTINUED

JET Programme, Tachikawa Kokusai Secondary Education School, Tokyo, Japan

2015 - 2018

Assistant Language Teacher

Prepared learning materials for English lessons, supervised school functions such as plays and speech contests, and organised events to showcase Japanese culture and heritage.

- Elected as Head Teacher of school's English Club.
- Selected as Cultural Exchange Ambassador.
- Originated mathematics and science curriculum for international students.

Digital Media Academy, Stanford University, Stanford, United States

2011

Assistant Film Production Teacher

Aided students in use of professional cameras and supported shooting process. Provided technical assistance in using post-production software and editing. Mentored students and supervised school trips.

- Hired by programme director by demonstrating outstanding achievements in short-film production.
- Entrusted with the formulization of the theoretical aspects of course material.

EDUCATION & COURSES

The University of Manchester

2011 - 2015

Bachelor of Arts Honours in Japanese and Screen Studies, Second Class

Earned knowledge in Japanese language skills, conceptualised papers on medieval history and contemporary sociology, and developed strong academic writing capabilities. Directed and produced short films and documentaries, operated industry-standard camera, lighting, and audio recording equipment, as well as edited footage and created visual effects, modelled, and textured graphics. Gained high-level theoretical information of filmmaking, editing, and production.

SOAS University of London

2019

Japanese Language Proficiency III

Graduated from the most advanced module of Japanese language that SOAS offer. I was able to continue pushing myself in regards to Japanese, including close reading of classical and highly formalised technical texts.

LANGUAGES & TECHINCAL PROFICIENCIES

ENGLISH	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet	PHOTOSHOP	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet	WORD	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet
JAPANESE	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet	PREMIERE PRO	• • • •	EXCEL	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet
PORTUGUESE	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet	INDESIGN	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet	SAGE 50	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ
NORWEGIAN	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet	3DS MAX	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet	POWERPOINT	\bullet

References and Media

Adrian Haddock, Tachikawa Kokusai School, adrianhaddock@googlemail.co.uk Linkedln: https://www.linkedin.com/in/matteus-gaarder-991494178/ Travis Schlafmann, Digital Media Academy, travis@digitalmediaacademy.org Jonathan Bunt, University of Manchester, jonathanbunt@manchester.ac.uk

Portfolio: https://matteusgaarder.myportfolio.com/